<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-21T19:22:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jean Njoroge</title><subtitle>My background and education has given me a strong foundation for using data to answer interesting questions and communicate about technical topics with diverse audience.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Beauty of Science</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-beauty-of-science/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beauty of Science" /><published>2017-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-beauty-of-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-beauty-of-science/">&lt;p&gt;I draw inspiration from creativity in science, and the ability to take and manipulate the science to benefit society.
I also draw creativity from great leaders of our times. Phil Jackson, he brought Zen into the chaotic environment, Colin Powel, Madeline Albirght (God knows I want to meet her).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, even though I am an engineer by training, some days, I feel like I am more of a scientist than an engineer, other days, I am a math whiz, coz I am fascinated by numbers. That which can amount to an absolute and even show a trend, that could predict what your shopping habits could be in the future, or used to preserve a product such that you can consume it at later date.
However, careewise I settled to being an Engineer, because I figured one can combined the science(exploring), engineering (application) and math (analysis) to invent, innovate and analysis to solve daunting problems.&lt;br /&gt;
You see, education, has always come easy to me, there is not a subject that I never excelled, whether it was history or physical education. I grasp things quick, I work quickly, and then I need to move to the next challenging thing. In essence, I need to be high on challenge. I am inhrently a problem-solver.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I draw inspiration from creativity in science, and the ability to take and manipulate the science to benefit society. I also draw creativity from great leaders of our times. Phil Jackson, he brought Zen into the chaotic environment, Colin Powel, Madeline Albirght (God knows I want to meet her).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome/Karibu!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome/Karibu!!" /><published>2017-09-22T20:15:03-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-22T20:15:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my%20blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Well! I finally got around to putting this old website together. Welcome to my all things data journal.  Here, you can read posts about data and learn with me as I explore the exciting word of machine learning technologies and big data. I am passionate about exploring the root issues behind relevant problems, and then using data to help build innovative products or find impactful solutions for millions of people around the world to improve the way people work and think.  Let’s learn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neat thing about it - powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and I can use Markdown to author my posts.
It actually is a lot easier than I thought it was going to be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Well! I finally got around to putting this old website together. Welcome to my all things data journal. Here, you can read posts about data and learn with me as I explore the exciting word of machine learning technologies and big data. I am passionate about exploring the root issues behind relevant problems, and then using data to help build innovative products or find impactful solutions for millions of people around the world to improve the way people work and think. Let’s learn together.</summary></entry></feed>